[Music]
the following is a production of Frankie
Freitas and the internet Museum of
holography
[Music]
hello this is Frankie Freitas and
welcome to holotalk the internet laser
and holography talk show our toll-free
number is
1-800-458-3525 or you can send an email
to holotalk
holoworld.com we've got telephone calls
we've got emails we've got special
guests coming up so thank you for tuning
in and let's get this week's show on the
road
hello everyone Frankie Freitas here with
another week of holotalk this week's
guest is Derek gallon from the Royal
holographic Art Gallery in British
Columbia Victoria British Columbia and
Derek's going to fill us in on some of
the aspects of his Gallery there in
Canada and it's also going to give us a
look into the new red star emulsions
that are coming out of Russia which
hopefully will be able to replace the AG
foe emulsions that are becoming very
hard to come by for doing Holograms just
an announcement this is going to be a
short show this is our holiday week
Debbie has the week off I'm here by
myself I'd like to say that next week
we're going to have a show where we're
going to make an announcement on our
1998 project here in the studio every
year we pick a new project
this project is going to be
reconstructing the Titanic
holographically what we're going to do
is take archival film footage and bring
it into the laboratory and create
three-dimensional Holograms from the
archival film footage that was shot on
the Titanic Expeditions so if you tune
in next week you'll be able to get
details on that now we're going to put
up a separate web page for this whole
process there's going to be a number of
people involved with it including local
students and some students out of the
Philadelphia area
and we're going to take you step by step
through this entire process you can do
this on your own if you're at a home
studio because everything that we're
going to do is going to be done with
homemade equipment and your desktop
computer
so even if you don't want to do a
hologram of the Titanic
you may have a hologram that you could
do of some video footage that you shot
maybe a wedding or the birth of a baby
or a birthday party or anything of that
nature a holographic portrait using a
camera and we're going to take you step
by step through this entire process and
how you can make one of these holograms
on your own of course the project that
we'll be working on will be the Titanic
footage so you just have to replace that
information with whatever type of
information you'd like to do with the
hologram on your own as a sidebar to
that information the
who will be heading up the other
students sort of like the manager of the
other students will be Julie Rosner in
the Philadelphia area and Julie is a
student who has been working with me
since she was in the second or third
grade I first met Julie and her brother
Ross at my laser and holography classes
at the Franklin Institute in
Philadelphia many years ago
she continued to come up to the studio
and learn about Holograms I've worked
with her family with several science
projects involving Holograms and lasers
and she's going to be heading up the
students for the Titanic project next
week we'll have a interview with Julie
so you can get to know her a little bit
better and if you're a student listening
to this this week and your own holiday
vacation you certainly want to tune in
next week which will be the 28th the
week of the 28th and hear a little bit
about Julie and how she's going to be
working on the project our musical guest
this week is a group called mitchif
Piven Piven and they are out of
Ukraine
now my daughter and I used to do cyber
casting of concerts and we went down to
the Philadelphia area and did a cyber
cast of this concert it translates I
believe to dead rooster and they're a
very very popular band in Ukraine so
they're going to be our guest tonight
and you'll see a separate link on the
holotalk page for them because we do the
musical broadcast in 2088 while just for
the voice broadcast of hollow Talk
itself just to keep the file size
smaller this comes to you at 14-4 so
after the show don't forget to click on
the link and listen to the music that we
recorded it live in Philadelphia of
midship Piven okay we're going to move
on right away to the interview with
Derek from the Royal holographic Art
Gallery after the interview Derek sent
an email to me saying that you know how
it is when you get interviewed you
always forget to say some of the things
that you want to say and he said just to
give an example of how popular home
milligrams are in his area of the
country
that they've had four break-ins
at his shop and had Holograms stolen so
people were taking a heck of a risk to
get in there and and take Holograms
that's incredible so let's move on to
the interview it lasts about 15 minutes
and the Royal holographic Art Gallery
also has a link on the whole talk page
and if you want to remember you can also
listen to the interview while you travel
over to the webpage itself which is
www.islandnet.com
Tilda Royal we'll take you right there
just click on the link so let's go to
our interview with Derek and see what he
has to say about holography in Canada
and also the new red star emulsions
which are coming out of Russia you're
talking to Derek gallon from Royal
holographic art gallery and Victoria
British Columbia why don't you tell some
of the listeners what they could find in
your gallery if they were to visit your
shop Frank we try to have as much as uh
as possible of different artists on a
different Hall run products we we try to
find a new products we constantly search
for them that's the reason we are able
to show a quite unique Russian Holograms
we started the partnership with the
Russian holographers more or less three
years ago we have a constant display of
our Russian holography
uh made mostly on that Russian glass
plate which is kind of difficult for
sitting but they are extremely high
quality as you know and they are very
interesting so we have like a one wall
devoted only to Russian holography most
of it is like a old Russian architect
from our museums but there is a few
modern art pieces
quite uh interesting display I would say
uh the other
Holograms we have are Larry liberman
multi-color hologram we have some other
Holograms from a Holland from that
holographic Studio
and uh we have the photopolymers with uh
made ones using very well-known Masters
from Mrs awesome as well as Mr Cherry so
they are quite a good yeah I have a
number of those myself they're
incredible holograms on the photo
polymer materials
absolutely thought that they are no more
available on the photopolymer you know
that's the bigger pieces and then we
have plenty of a smaller Holograms from
many many different Studios from all
over the world as well as the Holograms
we make ourselves
so if there's uh something for everybody
just something I would like to
especially point out is that the
traditional use for some smaller
Holograms like uh for gift industry
it's a kind of a limited in our opinion
so you have a trinkets you have pendants
keyrings and uh wall pictures
that's more or less it so we try to show
people uh new ways of using Holograms so
we mounted a couple of uh larger film
pieces in the Floor of our gallery on
the mounted directly on the wall so it
looks like a part of the wall like
looking through the window and quite a
simple trick that it is uh extremely
good effects and people are stunned by
the look of those Holograms now you have
a lot of these holograms on your website
don't you uh lead Friday's like uh my uh
hobby to I just love working on the
internet I love creating home pages
so yes we have a quite large website on
the
most of the stuff we have uh pictures
online that's right but some things you
can see under the gallery if we have
just a one or two pieces or something we
usually are not putting it on the net
let me just remind the listeners that
you can visit the Royal holographic Art
Gallery website
at
www.islandnet.com
tilde Royal slash index.html and we will
also include a link directly to the site
on the whole talk page and while you're
listening to this interview you can
click right on that link and go over and
visit the site because the real audio
player will continue to play as you go
place to place on the web so there's no
need to sit there and stare at your
computer while you're listening to this
just click on the Royal holographic Art
Gallery link and go over and visit the
site while you're listening to the
interview yes that's exactly what I did
when I listened to the interview you had
a last week with a hunter from China oh
okay it was extremely interesting
interview and uh we are very impressed
with the hard work those guys in China
are putting up to promote the holography
in China but there is something
interesting you know there is a hunter
in China said that many people is like
uh experiencing holograms for the very
first time we are in Canada it's like uh
you know
one of the leading countries in a
high-tech but still we have a quite many
people coming to our Gallery saying that
they're seeing programs for the very
first time no kidding yep isn't that
something question you can write a
separate book about that
you're also getting involved with uh
Russian emotions as well for a
holographic artists to use in their lab
now that Alexa has sort of crapped out
on us could you tell us a little bit
about the red star film well we are
using already this film to create our
own stock Holograms so this film is
already existing
it's a very high quality film
just we have some final
problems we have to solve before a
bigger distribution of this emotion of
the film
we had some problems with uh upgrading
uh light sensitivity and now we are
almost ready to set up the first samples
of this film actually we are I would say
Rarity is just with a Christmas trash we
have to hold down and just uh finish uh
south of our stocks existing Holograms
to the different hologram stores as we
are Hotel available on images
and simply after Christmas although
we'll we'll start Distributing the first
samples of the red star demographic film
let's let's hold for a minute on the uh
the sensitivity of the Emulsion how
close are you getting because I would
say that agsa is sort of like the
Benchmark of where people are used to
doing an exposure how close are we with
the Russian emulsions to that
sensitivity are we getting pretty close
to that now I'm not sure about the
films but what we are having in
Partnership as a joint venture with a
couple of Russian Lab
it's uh well we had some problems with a
very high sensitivity it was that those
Trend problem in a large volume we had a
problem with the emotion which was kind
of too soft under having problems drying
it up properly so I would say that we
have a very sensitive emotion that it's
at this stage it's simply not ready for
a big run in a small amount it's a
possible to manufacture that in a big
round it's it's it's it's kind of Hassle
and we cannot offer it yet what we are
the closest uh to act files says what we
have now is like a half of the answers
it's not bad but we hope for more so we
are working on it hard I think a lot of
holographers have the tendency to
overexpose for reflection Holograms
anyway I know I
up to twice the amount of exposure that
actually recommends whenever I wish you
a reflection hologram
so I think that's pretty close to uh
so you will get the samples too and then
you'll be able to evaluate yourself okay
you will like it how about the
processing is the processing that much
different than what you can do with the
actual emulsions
the process is processing we use is uh
quite different it takes up to 10
minutes to keep it in the developer
really yeah it's closer to just a
regular black and white film developing
it's this way without bleaching it's
just a
closer to photography no bleaching
that's amazing who the person you could
ever produce a reflection hologram
without bleaching I believe you follow
some samples of what we have and they
are quite bad they are very bright yeah
yeah I think you have to representative
emotion people that have 35 millilitis
they're not too concerned about it but
you know there's a ton of five milliwatt
lasers out there that people do this as
a hobby as amateurs it's hitting them
pretty hard because they just don't have
that stability you know to have that
long of an exposure time so it's
anything that can get close to what we
did see with accent is good now you can
also produce images for other people now
does someone send you a laser
transmission master
from scratch but right now we are just
working on a special custom order for
Oklahoma State University and uh it will
be eight by ten film hologram 500 copies
so we are working on sizes up to 11 by
14 right now prices are nice too I
understand well it's I would say less
than half of a regular prices for such
answer but I believe that you Frank
deserves to have your own interview
as well like you are interviewing some
other guys but what you did lately with
the photogram as I understand you you
were able to improve the quality
finishing the mastering touches with the
digital equipment yes I saw some uh
samples of a final result they are much
better than you they used to be so I
believe uh somebody has to call you one
day and do an interview with foreign
yeah the digital aspect has increased
the quality quite a bit because we were
working from 35 millimeter film
and anytime you take that up to any
large size you know you're going to get
grain and you're going to lose your
resolution
the ones that film that image has been
digitized once you have that digital
information you can do just about
anything you want to with it you can
even sharpen it up and rework it and
things so that that is a big jump
excellent now I will remind the
listening I've got the photogram is a
technique from developed so simply
anybody can just uh
make a picture using regular camera and
of the mega film song is able to create
the 3D hologram we had them and they
were quite nice so that's something
which is very interesting thank you very
much anything else you want to let our
listeners know before we head out for
this um
visitors on the internet visit us to the
side we have a quite a good traffic and
quite a big demand for Holograms the
newsletter we have online
newsletter now tell us a little about
the newsletter oh it's
just
about monthly emails with some updates
like in the new edition there will be
information about the closing out by Our
Heroes you know just a little facts of a
holographic Community as well as some
basic information about holography and
the processing used in holography it's
just like a you know a little short
newsletter with introduction you feature
artists I think Sharon McCormick yes
still we have Sharon arm and uh
there will be a new guest in a probably
next couple of weeks again after
Christmas yes I will have more time to
to finish new page actually tell us who
it is uh
we um
hello it will be about Rudy oh really
yeah and the whole page will be changed
there I'm working on a new image of our
page it's always because again I visited
your page I feel ashamed
um always behind you and I try to get
closer when I'm closer than you do a
move and I'm back again so
actually I'm so impressed with your page
like
every time I visit it goes up on its
kind of better and better I have no idea
what it is it's just really just a
simple thing it's just a simple thing
Sharon McCormick's going to be on the
show by the way she's going to do an
interview I'm really looking forward to
having her on the show it's not going to
be until probably fall I would imagine
because the show's book now until the
end of September of 98. oh wow which
surprised me but I'm happy that that
happened so Sharon's going to be a guest
on the show towards fall she's on
vacation right now I believe she's in
Baja and maybe I shouldn't say where she
is I don't know
yes we hope to have a her exhibition in
Victoria BC sometime next year we are
working on it too okay well Derek thank
you very much for being on the show
and I hope you get a lot of traffic on
your page from listeners to whole talk
are you running any specials right now
oh yes we have like a whole seasonal
like another half of the page promoting
uh I would say 15 the most popular
Holograms from the Hologram product do
you have any more readers
no you know we are
thinking about creating some similar
Holograms because of the Russian
Partners you know I had a Rita and it
was stolen
and then I saw that you had a few and I
got one from you
and it's one of my favorite Holograms I
think it's so neat but I put it
somewhere so that it would be safe
and I cannot find where I put it
it's gone it's around here somewhere I
don't know whether I put it in a book
like in an encyclopedia book and put the
book back on the Shelf
it's gone I can't find it
so Monday I'm gonna have to go through
everything and see if I can't find my
Rita hologram because that is one of my
favorite Holograms I love that
nice piece small but nice yeah all right
Derek well take care what time is it out
there uh we just have our 15 after seven
okay
I didn't keep you up
take care and thank you very much for
being on holotalk thank you very much
all right take care
so there we have the Derek Gallen
interview from Royal holographic Art
Gallery I'd like to thank Derek for
agreeing to be a guest on the show and
also thank all of the other people
involved with the field of lasers and
holograms for agreeing to be on the show
for the 1998 year we are booked until
the end of September and I will try my
best to bring you interesting
programming every week so that if you
have a computer and an internet
connection you can just log on and hear
about the field that we all know and
love which is the field of lasers and
Holograms
I imagine we have a lot of new listeners
this week I'd be willing to bet that
deal with a ton of computers under the
Christmas tree and more than likely
they're set up and they're running now
towards the end of the week so if you're
a new listener and you've just joined us
welcome and I hope you continue to come
back and enjoy Hollow talk every week as
well
don't forget on the 28th and for the
entire week of the 28th we're going to
be announcing our 1998 holography
project here at my own personal studio
and that's going to be the
Reconstruction of the Titanic
holographically from archival film
footage that was shot during the
expeditions to the Titanic itself
I will back that up with some web-based
material so anyone who may be an amateur
or hobbyist holographer and have some
equipment on your own you may want to
try this so Debbie Lee will be back next
week she asked me to wish you all a
happy holiday season if you happen to
celebrate the holidays this time of the
year No Matter What holiday it is and
and myself I'd like to wish you the same
thing and have a safe one and I hope
that you have the opportunity to share
it with loved ones as well so this is
Frank de Freitas for holotalk and I'll
see you next week